Guide to the Jerry Hultin Collection RG.041
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
Jerry Hultin Collection
1872-2012
2004-2007
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
Hultin, Jerry MacArthur, 1942-
RG.041
3 Linear Feet in 2 boxes and 2 plaques
Item Frame rack
Box 1
Box 2
Biographical / Historical
Jerry MacArthur Hultin was the tenth Poly president, directing Polytechnic University from 2005 until 2013, after which it officially merged with New York University. Before his tenure at Poly, he served as Under Secretary of the Navy from 1997 to 2000 and as the dean of the Howe School of Technology Management at Stevens Institute of Technology from 2000 to 2005.
Scope and Contents
This collection mainly contains materials from an energy simulation in 2007 as well as miscellaneous documents and items from Jerry Hultin's tenure at Poly. Some items relate to Hultin's earlier career in the Navy and at Stevens Institute of Technology.
Arrangement
Materials in box two were received directly from Hultin's office and left in their original order with loose files gathered into "Miscellaneous" folders. Constructed titles are in brackets.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open for research without restriction.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials were transferred from the President's Office in the Jacobs Administrative Building on 6/29/2017.
Business cards; Audiovisual materials; Videotapes; Plaques (flat objects); Laptop computers; Hultin, Jerry MacArthur, 1942-
- Distinguished leadership award to Hultin as President of Poly, 2008 (Item Frame rack, Object 1)
- Plaque with part of Pentagon wall, 1998 (Item Frame rack, Object 2)
- Jerry Hultin's laptop and floppy disk drive, undated (Box 1, Object 1-2)
- Box of business cards, undated (Box 1, Object 3)
- "Building Social Business" by Muhammad Yunus, with note from Jerry Hultin on first page, 2010 (Box 1, Object 4)
- Wall Street Journal Student Achievement Award (Polytechnic University, Division of Management), 1987-1994 (Box 1, Object 5)
- Wall Street Journal Student Achievement Award (PINY, Division of Management), 1976-1986 (Box 1, Object 6)
- Paperweight of Polytechnic 150th Anniversary & Inauguration ticket in resin, 2005 (Box 2, Object 1)
- News 12 Brooklyn video tape - Charles Camarda visits Poly, 2005 (Box 2, Object 2)
- News 12 Brooklyn video tape - News 12 name Poly student "Student of the Week", 2005 (Box 2, Object 3)
- Video tape of 2004 Lynford Lecture (Box 2, Object 4)
- 150th and Inauguration September 2005, 1955, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Raison detre, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- History of Research Universities, 1872, 1876, 1896, 1902, 2005, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Polytechnic History/Inaugurals, 1900, 1933, 1950s, 1975, 1993, 2005, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
- [Drawing a Picture of Our Future], 2005-2006 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- [Energy Simulation Materials], 2007, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
- JMH Letters and Notes May 2005 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Chinese Energy Futures Game November 2006 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- [Simulation Book & Post-Simulation Report], 2007 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Energy Simulation, Central Party School and Pentagon, Beijing, 2005-2007, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Politique Americaine, Naval Policy in Asia, 2005-2007 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Framed "Fore 'n Aft" cover with image of Hultin, 1999 (Box 2, Object 5)
- "New Role for Jerry Hultin" memo, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Commencement speech 2012 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Commencement Remarks 2010 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Ursula Burns Honorary Degree Script, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 15)